[KAZUMA]
Some "Divine Treasure" huh?
♪
Sure, I knew
there was a time limit,
but it wore off fast.
[gasps]
[screams]
Eris, if this is your idea
of a joke,
I'm not laughin'!
- [AQUA] Hey, Kazuma.
- [KAZUMA] I'm Kazuma.
[AQUA] You just love
calling me an "idiot"
but, now I'm sure of something.
You must be, like, an idiot
of the highest caliber,
aren't you?
Oh, come on,
you don't understand!
Walkin' around the castle,
everybody was waiting
on me hand and foot!
So, I started thinkin'
I could get away
with just about anything!
Then, that makes you
a stupid idiot
who really needs to think
about what he did!
[KAZUMA]
Man, even Iris was mad at me!
Don't know if Big Brother
can go on living!
[NOBLE 06-A (F)] Oh, look
there, it's the big talker.
[NOBLE 06-C (M)] Why
Lady Dustiness ever associated
with someone like that
is quite beyond me.
[NOBLE 06-A (F)]
It makes no sense!
[CLAIRE] Princess Iris has
already retired for the night.
[KAZUMA]
She has?
So, this is goodbye.
You're free to stay here
and enjoy the festivities.
[CLAIRE] Assuming that
you actually have the nerve
to do so.
[squeaks]
[CLAIRE]
Konosuba.
[KAZUMA]
This sucks!
What the hell
is that chick's problem?
Even at the very end, she just
had to get some digs in!
I mean, sure, it's my fault,
I totally admit that!
But, I just wanted to stay
in the castle
a little bit longer!
[thudding]
Huh?
[door creaking opens]
You can keep asking,
but my answer won't change.
Now, now there's no need
to act like that.
Right, guess I might
as well tell you,
the Divine Treasure
that swaps bodies
is here in the castle.
But I don't see
what's so dangerous about it.
Well, the thing is,
if for any reason,
the body that's been
swapped gets killed
it then becomes
a permanent change.
Huh?
When used a certain way,
this thing can potentially
let a person
to go on living forever.
Once your body slows down
and starts aging,
you simply find a young,
healthy person to switch with
and then kill them
once you're in their body.
That sounds
pretty messed up to me!
Maybe we should
tell someone and--
That's the worst thing
either of us could do.
If people hear
what this item's capable of
you do know
what'll happen next, right?
♪
'Cause I have no doubt.
Nobles will come from all over
hoping to steal it
for themselves.
[KAZUMA] It's the power
of eternal life, huh?
I've chosen to share
all this with you
'cause I know
you won't misuse it,
in case you're wondering.
[KAZUMA]
Huh?
Does she seriously
trust me this much?
[CHRIS] So, it seems
you and the princess
have become playmates lately,
haven't you?
Well, if you think
you're feeling up to it
wanna go play now?
[giggles]
Huh?
[indistinct chatter]
We're in luck.
Since there's
a big party going on
the security seems light.
Yeah, it does.
Hey, why're you
dressed like that?
I don't want anyone
knowing who I am, either.
A really shady guy working
in a magic item shop
handed me this mask.
He said it's one of the hottest
things in the store.
Oh?
Right, time to go.
[CHRIS]
You ready, minion?
Yep, I'm ready
when you are, big lady.
Let's move.
[sighs]
Look, could you not
refer to me as "Big Lady?"
Then maybe you
shouldn't call me "minion."
You ever think about that?
I'm the one who made a name
for herself as a noble thief.
You do remember, right?
Okay, let's go.
We should settle this
over rock-paper-scissors.
Sounds good, you're on!
[KAZUMA]
Bring it!
- [KAZUMA] Rock, paper...
- [CHRIS] Rock, paper...
[crickets chirping]
[CHRIS]
Tell me, assistant,
is that where
we'll find the princess?
Yeah, right, boss.
[KAZUMA] Of all the times
to lose at rock-paper-scissors.
Even I can't manage scaling
a castle wall that high.
Snipe!
♪
[metal clanging]
Aah, you're pretty handy, assistant.
♪
[footsteps]
It's been
smooth sailing so far.
[gasps]
♪
Hey, boss, my enemy detection's
picking something...
[sniffing]
Hey, assistant?
Since you have the Lurk skill,
do we really need
to stick so close
together like this?
This is no time
to be careless, boss!
We can't afford
to take up much space!
- Get closer!
- Whoa, that's too close!
This is to maintain the world's
peace, and, uh, other stuff!
Hang in there, please,
oh, you have to!
If you don't stop
what you're doing right now
you're gonna bring
about Eris' divine wrath!
Intruders,
they're here in the castle!
[GUARD 06-B (M)]
Get out here, men, now!
[horn blowing]
See what can happen
when you yell like that, boss?
We're gonna need
to have a long talk
when all this is over!
Whatever, now's not
the time to be fighting!
[CHRIS]
I have heard enough out of you!
[GUARD 06-C (M)] Princess Iris
is on the top floor, stop them!
[panting]
Create Water!
[KAZUMA]
Freeze.
Whoa...
[grunting]
[GUARD 06-C (M)]
Oh, my coccyx.
- [GUARD 06-A (M)] Stop!
- Nice move, my assistant.
Hey, try complimenting less
and helping out more, boss!
Okay.
Stand back as I show you
what I can do?
♪
Wire Trap!
Whoa, you could've
used that a little sooner.
All right, that should
buy us some time.
[CLAIRE] You just cut off
your only escape route.
[sword scraping]
And now you two
don't have anywhere to run!
It's gone from bad to worse.
[gasps]
Up there.
[CHRIS]
That's how we're getting out.
[KAZUMA]
What? No.
Wait, if I'm gonna be kicked
out of the capital tomorrow
then I would rather take care
of all this tonight!
Huh?
Hang on, since when have you
ever said something like that?
[gasps]
[KAZUMA]
She's right.
What the hell's gotten into me?
Gotta calm down
I'm normally
way more levelheaded.
Yeah, once I get back to Axel,
I can finally relax a little.
[IRIS] With the way
things are these days
it's not a good time
to immerse myself in studies.
So, uh, I was hoping you would
play this game with me.
Please?
Simple, you aren't
like the others.
Everyone dotes on me,
but you never do that.
You're rude and so honest.
Hey, I wasn't asking you
to roll out
a huge list of complaints.
Right, and that's exactly what
I've been trying to tell you.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
[gasps]
Listen, boss I, uh...
I think I'm gonna
have to get serious.
[CHRIS]
You what?
- Enough chatter!
- [sword slashing]
[gasps]
Uh-oh!
[screams]
So, um... what skill's that?
[sword clanging]
[chuckles]
Sorry this one's
my little secret.
Top condition! Top condition!
I'm not sure why,
but I am in top condition!
[gasps]
[laughing]
[KAZUMA]
Increased magic power!
Improved circulation!
A clearer complexion!
Tonight, I'll display
my true strength!
[gasps]
[laughs]
Look out!
We are the Silver-Haired
Thief Brigade!
[grunts]
Spare yourselves
excruciating pain
and clear a path.
[screams]
♪
[GUARD 06-C (M)]
He's strong, amazing!
[GUARD 06-D (M)]
Even with that weird mask!
[screams]
[gasps]
Lightning, Skill Bind!
[RAIN]
What?
Hey, I don't like
"Silver-Haired Thief Brigade!"
Starting now,
you can be the boss.
So, I think we should go
with "Masked Thief Brigade!"
[KAZUMA]
That's not for me.
I'd rather not be treated
like a criminal mastermind.
So, guess what,
I don't want to, either!
[laser firing]
♪
[footsteps]
[MITSURUGI] Claire,
you're facing a vicious foe.
[BOTH]
Hmm.
♪
But, now, I am here.
Please allow a Swordmaster
to bring down this masked man!
♪
And, to you,
I leave the silver-haired boy
to be swiftly dispatched.
♪
[CHRIS]
Hey, assistant.
Do you think I look like
a boy that much?
Maybe he noticed you're built
straight up and down.
[whimpering]
It's time to get a grip!
This is a critical juncture!
As soon as I Steal
his cursed sword.
It would appear that
you're going to use Steal.
But, unfortunately...
ever since losing
to one who wields it,
I've prepared counter-measures,
where I--
Steal!
It's no use!
- Wait... [gasps]
- Freeze...
[KAZUMA]
And one more, Freeze.
[whimpering]
[groaning]
♪
Huh?!
Hmm...
Huh, Create Water!
[screams]
- Sir Mitsurugi?
[laughing]
[KAZUMA]
What idiot would dare take
a Swordmaster head-on?
Your weakness
is overconfidence!
[laughing]
Oh, so these
are negative emotions.
Savory, quite savory indeed.
[CLAIRE]
Damn you!
[KAZUMA]
Away!
[laughing]
I would advise looking after
that man immediately!
Sir Mitsurugi!
[CLAIRE] Quickly, Rain,
he'll need healing magic!
[RAIN]
C-Coming!
Boss, this way!
Oh, no!
You can't escape
with Princess Iris ahead!
Stop them, all of you!
[all gasping]
[laughing]
It seems that
we're nearly to Iris' room!
Copy that, assistant!
[KAZUMA]
Top condition, top condition!
I'm in top condition now!
[sword clanking]
That is far enough, intruder.
To protect the kingdom,
and its royalty
I shall not allow you to pass.
[DARKNESS]
Therefore...
So-So, what are we
gonna do now, assistant?
[DARKNESS] Hey, do not close
the door on me!
What in the world
are you two trying to...
[gasps]
[both whimpering]
♪
[IRIS]
Intruders.
I am quite impressed
that you made it this far.
But, the Hero's blood's
in my veins
and, like the rest
of my family,
I've worked hard
to maintain that strength.
I swear upon this ring
that has been passed down
throughout my--
Move out of the way!
A couple of intruders
will be no match for my--
[gasps]
They look so cool!
What should we do now,
Darkness?
These noble thieves
have incredible style!
[MEGUMIN] This one's wearing
such a unique mask
and that black
costume's amazing!
What's your name?
Please tell me you've already
selected a name for your gang!
And Bind.
[gasps]
That's so cool!
Oh, my, I know!
[AQUA]
Sacred Break Spell!
[both whimpering]
[chuckles]
Really sorry to break it to ya
but all of your luck ran out
when you ran into me.
I have no idea
what you're looking for
but if I catch the two of you
bet that'll be enough to earn
me some more fancy bubbly!
Now, be good thieves
and surrender, okay?
[KAZUMA]
That little...
What's the hold up, Darkness?
Megumin's totally lost it
for some weird reason,
which means
you're our only hope!
Right!
Okay, use Steal
when we're making our escape.
On the Divine Treasure, right?
But, won't your Steal be, uh...
You think it only works
on underwear, huh?
- Princess Iris!
- You coward!
Such dirty tricks!
Let's attack them
from both sides!
[gasps]
And now
you will face my full...
- Come on!
- Face my full... powered swing!
♪
Yep, that's our
knucklehead Crusader!
[gasps]
Princess Iris!
Now!
- Steal!
[glass shattering]
Yes, all right, let's go!
[CHRIS]
We'll have to jump from here!
Where's my necklace?
Now I dunno
what you just ripped off
but I am not gonna stand here
and let you get away with it!
What an idiot,
stop making problems!
[grunts]
[KAZUMA]
Damn it all!
♪
They're gone!
Wow, that's so cool!
[sighs]
♪
You've got to calm yourself!
Just calm down, please!
[yelping]
Let go of my head!
You're gonna do
some serious damage!
I didn't want to,
but she forced me into it!
This was all Chris' idea!
Excuse me,
what is your problem?
Ow, ow, ow!
You recovered
the Divine Treasure
because it was
too dangerous, is that right?
Then, why not tell me
that from the very beginning?
My-My assistant didn't want
a link between you
and the noble thief.
He thought it could only
put you in a bad position!
[crying]
Co-Come on,
don't tell her everything!
[whimpering]
Honestly, you two.
Is anything else
being hidden from me?
[grunting]
Oh, it seems there is.
Wait, is that her...
I figured it would work better
if we did it at the same time.
Why does your Steal
only work on things
that aren't meant to be stolen?
Well at least it wasn't
panties this time!
Okay, that's not the point!
♪
Listen, Kazuma.
Do not lose this
and tell no one you have it.
Do you understand?
Keeping this secret is vital,
so take it
to the grave with you.
Whoa, knock it off, would ya!
If it's really that important,
I can say I found
the ring somewhere
and give it right back!
- Idiot!
- [screams]
This ring was intended
for the princess' engagement,
to be removed
and worn by her true love.
[gasps]
Now, with it being stolen,
the idea of some
random adventurer finding it.
If you returned the ring
out of good will
you would still be killed
to keep it all under wraps.
Yeah, that's pretty scary!
Princess Iris,
she loved that ring
and always held onto it.
So, you must never forget,
take good care of it
and never tell
anyone about this.
♪
[sighs]
[RAIN] We weren't aware
of the necklace's
dangerous power.
Thank you for informing us,
Lady Dustiness.
Yes.
But, you, on the other hand,
you were absolutely useless,
yet again,
on the night in question.
[whimpering]
[IRIS]
Could it be...
that the thieves did this
in an effort to protect me?
Well, if that's so,
then it would mean
the rumors we've been hearing
have all been truthful,
they really are noble.
I doubt it.
However, if there
is some validity to this
then I have to admit,
they are quite impressive.
[KAZUMA]
What was that?
Do you mean
the man wearing the mask?
Oh, he was so incredible!
That mask,
and that black costume.
They all speak
directly to my values!
Next time he's here, I have
to ask him for an autograph!
[KAZUMA]
Oh, man, this is a tough one.
I really wanna tell 'em
it was me.
[gasps]
[AQUA] What's the matter
with you, Kazuma?
How come you're grinning
like that, it's creepy.
Yes, she's right.
What are you suddenly
so happy about?
[whimpering]
[IRIS]
I agree.
In regard to that noble thief.
I must say, I was impressed.
[KAZUMA] Wait a minute,
is this the thing
where she actually
realizes who it really was?
I'm sure that, in the end,
the two of them
did what they did,
because they felt
genuinely concerned for me.
But, as I said, when it comes
to that particular noble thief.
[deep sigh]
I think I may be
a fan of his, myself.
[KAZUMA]
Okay, time for the big reveal.
What is the matter, Kazuma?
Why did you stand up
so suddenly?
Come on, you can tell me,
no need to make me guess!
Do you need to go pee,
is that it?
[DARKNESS]
Pitiful, if you will excuse me,
I can remove this fool!
Okay, I'll pee right here then!
Let go
or I'll Drain Touch your--
[IRIS]
I wonder.
Where are they?
And what are they doing
right now?
Mainly...
that attractive
silver-haired thief.
♪
[sighs]
[KAZUMA]
Yeah, Konosuban.
[IRIS]
I'm sad to see you go, but...
[sighing]
...Elder Brother, if possible
I do have one request.
[gasps]
Please allow me to speak,
Princess Iris.
[gasps]
This man has taken down many
of the Devil King's generals.
In fact, he may even defeat
the Devil King, in due time.
But that is a difficult mission
as I'm sure you can imagine.
So, as he faces down
such a dismaying task
could you offer him
some words of encouragement?
[KAZUMA] Hang on just a minute
what the hell did she just say?
He wants to beat
the Devil King?
Is that true?
Please tell me, Elder Brother,
is that really something
you have in your plans?
[KAZUMA]
Yeah, right, I could never...
[whimpering]
♪
[clearing throat]
Well, y'know,
if I get the chance,
I'd definitely consider
slaying him,
I...guess.
[all chuckle]
I just know you can do it,
Elder Brother!
I wish you good luck
in defeating him!
That's it,
I can't take this anymore!
Could you please stop
calling him "Elder Brother?"
After all, you do have
an actual older brother, right?
You want to fawn over someone,
try that with him!
Besides, I'm gonna be the one
who takes down the Devil King,
so Kazuma won't have
anything to do!
No, maybe you're the one
who doesn't understand!
Elder Brother
is my Elder Brother!
So, why is it wrong for me
to refer to him that way?
Besides, if you were the one
who brought down
the Devil King, then there'd
be no point to it at all!
This is something
I want him to do!
Not you,
am I making myself clear?
I ask you to stop
and you start spamming
the Elder Brother button?
You wanna pick a fight,
'cause, get ready to lose!
Well, we'll just
see about that!
We royals are all
pretty strong, you know!
You dare challenge me,
"princess!"
Stop this at once!
The two of you were getting
along so well yesterday!
[CLAIRE] Princess Iris, you
must try and restrain yourself!
You've never been
in a fight before!
- Please, Princess.
- [sighs]
So, what was it
you were gonna ask me?
[KAZUMA]
Anything you like.
[sighs]
Why yes, of course.
I wanted to ask you...
[gasps]
♪
Hmm.
Since we didn't have
a chance to settle our game.
I wondered if you'd come
and play with me again.
[chuckles]
♪
- [KAZUMA] KO!
- [AQUA] NO!
- [DARKNESS] SU!
- [MEGUMIN] BA!
[screams]
You really need
to quiet down.
Go outside of town if you want
to cause such a disturbance.
Things were going well,
and then you screwed me over!
[KAZUMA] When you started in
with all that crap
about me bringing down
the Devil King,
Iris probably had to totally
change her plans!
Bet she wanted me
to stay there,
or she wanted to go out with me
or maybe even sleep in my bed!
Now, that
is utterly ridiculous.
After one week,
you think you are capable
of convincing somebody like her
to fall head over heels
in love with you?
[DARKNESS]
Time to face reality.
Promise you won't drag me
back out there!
I don't wanna be fact-checked
about any of this stuff!
[whimpering]
[KAZUMA] For the time being
let me dream a little more.
Your most precious ring
stolen by thieves.
We deserve
to receive your punishment.
[IRIS] I know the two of you
did everything you could.
So, please, don't be upset.
We're grateful for your mercy.
Hmm.
♪
[IRIS] A special rule
has been linked to that ring.
Whoever shows true courage
and manages
to slay the Devil King
will be commended,
and given the right
to take the Princess
as their bride.
Big Brother.
I hope you keep
my ring close to you
and take good care of it.
♪
[ALDARP]
My Divine Treasure.
Not only was it stolen
by the thief,
but they've taken things
a step further
by sealing it away as well?
Find it, now!
[DEVIL 06-A (M)]
That isn't possible.
If the Divine Treasure's
been sealed
then there's nothing I can do.
You are little more
than a useless wretch!
[ALDARP]
Must I wait forever?
When are you actually
going to grant my wish?
[breathing heavily]
[SYLVIA]
It's your devoted Sylvia!
And I am really starting
to get into this vacation.
I find it so liberating!
And extremely satisfying!
It seems...